记录片之家倾情奉献
http://www.jlpzj.com/
本字幕仅供学习交流，严禁用于商业用途
翻译/时间轴/校对:laser
青蛙在地球上  生存了超过2亿5千万年
Narrator: frogs have managed to navigate life on earth for more than 250 million years.
青蛙是从水域走向陆地的首个动物祖先
They were the first of our ancestors to venture from the water to the world beyond.
[蛙叫声]
[ croaks ]
青蛙前期象鱼类的身躯 并不会阻止他们向陆地前进
But their fish-like beginnings haven't hindered their progress on earth.
青蛙演变出多种多样的品种
They've evolved into an explosion of species,
每一种都独一无二
Each one unique.
这些微小的“时间旅行者” 经历了恐龙、小行星和冰河时代
These diminutive time travelers survived the dinosaurs, asteroids, and ice ages,
适应能力令人难以想象
Adapting in ways that boggle the mind.
有些青蛙是伪装之王
Some are masters of camouflage,
有些青蛙皮肤上带有毒物 以避开掠食者
While others avoid predators by carrying poisons in their skin.
青蛙的生存技能 使其演变出数以千计的品种
Their survival tactics have splintered them into thousands of species,
青蛙遍布地球的每一个角落
Scattered on almost every corner of the earth.
无论是蜥蜴、青蛙 还是蟾蜍
Whether salamander... Frog... Or toad...
两栖动物是地球上 品种最多、分布最广的动物
Amphibians are some of the most diverse and far-flung animals on the planet...
但是青蛙的数量正在下降 专家很担心
But they're disappearing, and experts are worried.
青蛙被认为是 环境的预警
Frogs are considered bellwethers for the environment.
青蛙的水陆生活是独一无二的
Their double life makes them unique.
青蛙用皮肤来呼吸、饮水
It's through their skin that they breathe and drink.
青蛙皮肤的渗透能力非常强
Because their skin is so permeable,
因此青蛙对环境的变化十分敏感
They're especially sensitive to changes in the environment.
目前 超过三分之一的两栖动物的数量在下降
Today, more than a third of amphibians are in decline.
澳洲、美洲的青蛙都在减少
From australia to south america, frogs are disappearing.
生存了无数年代的青蛙 为什么突然垮下了?
Why are species that have survived for eons suddenly collapsing?
为了避免其它物种 遭遇同样的命运 科学家正在寻找原因
Scientists are searching for clues, before the next species slips away.
[蛙叫声]
[ frogs croaking ]
青蛙是隐秘的
Frogs can be secretive.
要找出答案 你必须到那些阴暗的地方
To find answers, one must probe the shadows.
[蛙叫声]
[ frogs croaking ]
这只玻璃蛙的皮肤是透明的 可以看到她的卵
This glass frog's translucent skin reveals her eggs.
交配是危险的事情
Coupling can be a dangerous proposition.
青蛙及其后代在食物链中 扮演着重要的角色
Frogs -- and their offspring -- are key players in the food chain.
父母会分别离开 留下蛙卵自力更生
The parents will go their separate ways, leaving their eggs to fate.
附近叶子上的另一只青蛙 看上去有点相似
On a nearby leaf, another frog looks similar,
但他有不同的繁殖策略
But his species has a different tactic.
老爸会守护孩子直到卵孵化 他会日夜守护孩子
This father will stand watch over his young he'll guard them night and day.
两栖动物非凡的生存历史
The extraordinary life history of amphibians
就像这个老爸与孩子一样 经历了几百万年
Has played out like this for millions of years,
但是环境变化很快
But conditions are rapidly changing --
无论是在雨林深处 还是在海边的沙质岩石
Whether deep in the rain forest, or on a sandy outcrop at the ocean's edge.
在美国科德角最高处 生物遭遇第一场春雨
On the tip of cape cod, life is stirring with the first spring rain.
锄足蟾像野花一样 从沙地冒出来
Spadefoot toads sprout like strange flowers from the sand.
他们要到清新的水池产卵
They'll make their way to vernal pools, to lay their eggs.
如果蟾蜍无法来到 供繁殖的水池 数量就会逐渐减少
If toads can't get to their breeding ponds, the population will gradually vanish.
在东北部 人类几乎令锄足蟾完全灭绝
In the northeast, spadefoot toads are being edged out by humans.
这是是国家海滨科德角
Here at the cape cod national seashore,
虽然土地受到保护 蟾蜍依然受伤害
The land is protected, but the roads can still take a toll.
当两栖动物在全球的栖息地被瓜分
Amphibians all over the world face a deadly collision course
它们正面临致命的冲突
When their habitat is carved up.
如果雌性两栖动物正在排卵期 下一代也同样被毁掉了
If a female is full of eggs, the next generation is lost, as well.
科德角国家海滨已经采取预防措施
Cape cod national seashore has begun to take precautions
在温暖、多雨的的夜晚 每一次努力都会带来很大的改观
On warm, rainy nights. Every little effort makes a big difference.
当两栖动物与人类发生冲突时 每年数以百万的两栖动物都死亡了
Millions of amphibians are lost each year when they collide with humans.
地球上有多少条公路?
How many millions of roads crisscross the globe?
过去50年 人口增加了一倍
Human population has doubled in the last 50 years.
两栖动物几乎在各个地方都受到打击
Amphibians are getting hit from almost every front.
这些超级生存家的进化速度 赶不上环境的变化
These super-survivors can't evolve quickly enough to keep up with the changes.
我们已经给青蛙造成了完美的风暴
We've stirred up the perfect storm for frogs.
[雷鸣]
[ thunder crashes ]
在这种混乱上 再添加一种神秘的疾病
Add a mysterious disease to the mix,
情况会变得生死攸关
And the situation becomes critical.
青蛙的数量在下降 即使是在地球上最原始的地方
We're now losing frogs even in the most pristine corners of the earth.
在约塞米蒂国家公园
In yosemite national park,
黄腿山蛙在这里生存了几百万年
The mountain yellow-legged frog has maintained a foothold for millions of years.
它们经历了冰河期
They've survived ice ages and glaciers.
连蝌蚪的生命力都非常强
Even their tadpoles are tough enough
蝌蚪可以经历几个冬天 直到变态为成体蛙
To weather multiple winters until metamorphosis.
但是现在 他们的麻烦来了
But today, they're in trouble --
专家试图找出原因
And experts have been struggling to figure out why.
Roland Knapp博士首次确认 一个原因
Dr.Roland Knapp was one of the first to identify one of the causes.
过去这里有很多青蛙
Knapp: historically, there were lots of frogs here.
有记录表明 经过湖边
Records suggest that walking along the lakeshore
你会看到一个接一个的青蛙跳入湖中
You would just see frog after frog plopping into the water.
现在 走遍整个湖
And now you can walk the entire lakeshore
一个青蛙也没看到
And not see a single frog.
20世纪初 为了建立悠闲的钓鱼场所
In the beginning of the 1900s, to create recreational fisheries,
大家把外地的鲑鱼
People began moving non-native trout
放入本来无鱼的湖中
Into many of these naturally fishless lakes.
鲑鱼以青蛙为食 大部分的湖里
Trout prey on the frogs, and in most of these places,
青蛙已经毫无踪影了
The frogs are now gone.
Knapp博士小组努力清除 约塞米蒂国家公园的湖中的鲑鱼
Argo: Knapp has been part of an intensive effort to remove fish from yosemite's lakes.
好像青蛙又回到湖中了
It looked like the frogs were making a comeback...
但是青蛙又成为 更凶狠的真菌的猎物
Until they fell prey to something even more insidious.
杀鱼行动之后不久 我们发现
Knapp: it wasn't long after we began the fish eradications that we realized
除了鲑鱼以外 还有其它威胁
That there was something else going on besides just fish.
即两栖壶菌
And that something is the amphibian chytrid fungus.
12年前
Argo: twelve years ago,
Knapp博士发现 死蛙出现在研究地点
Knapp started finding dead frogs at his study sites.
开始死因是个谜
At first the deaths were a mystery...
直到他确认了一种奇怪的真菌
Until a strange fungus was identified.
壶菌攻击青蛙的皮肤 造成缺氧
It seems to attack the skin of a frog, depriving it of oxygen.
你看到这种情况会很难过
Knapp: it's really hard to see
你给青蛙加了标签 后来又抓了几次
An animal that you've tagged, you've recaptured several times,
有时候你几个小时都在观察它
You've watched them for hours sometimes...
最后你发现它死在湖中
And then you find that same animal dead in a pool.
这种病杀死了青蛙
This disease is taking the species out.
仅仅几十年 壶菌病
Argo: in a matter of decades, chytridiomycosis, or "chytrid,"
就发展成 全球的流行病
Has become a global epidemic.
这就像青蛙的黄热病
Woman: it's almost like we're seeing the yellow fever of frogs
或者1918年的流感病
Or the flu of 1918.
我们还不清楚这种病的发病机理
We haven't figured out how this disease even works,
为何传染如此之快
How it spreads so quickly.
在加州大学伯克利分校 Mary stice正在试图
Argo: at u.c. Berkeley, mary stice is trying to uncover
找出壶菌病的更多发病机理
More clues about chytrid.
这些小圈是游动孢子
Stice: these little circles are zoospores,
处于真菌感染阶段
And that's the infectious stage of the fungus.
孢子在水中游动
It swims through the water,
寻找下一个受害者 即蝌蚪或成体蛙
Looking for its next victim -- a tadpole or an adult frog.
壶菌病的最大谜团是
The most puzzling thing about this disease
我们不知道壶菌来自哪里
Is that we have no idea where it's from.
有人在保存的标本中找到壶菌
It's found in preserved specimens
包括19世纪40年代的非洲标本
From the 1930s, in africa,
70年代的加利福尼亚的标本
From the '70s here in california,
在我工作的约塞米蒂国家公园
But it looks like it's a new disease moving into populations.
壶菌病看上去是 一种新引入的疾病
Up in yosemite, where I do my fieldwork,
情况很糟糕
It's looking pretty bleak.
我真的很担心
I am really worried.
我们知道 真菌靠水生存
Argo: we know that the fungus needs water to survive.
真菌也需要宿主
It also needs a host.
但是我们不知道 真菌是怎样蔓延的
But we don't know how it moves,
以及在真菌到来时 怎样阻止它
Or how to contain it once it arrives.
真菌不像鱼类
Knapp: Unlike the fish,
我们可以控制鱼的数量
Where we actually had some control over those fish populations,
我们可以清除某个湖的鱼
And we could remove them from selected lakes,
但我们不能控制 两栖壶菌的数量
We don't have that ability with the amphibian chytrid fungus.
很大程度上 我们只能做的是 坐视不管
All we can do right now, for the most part, is watch it do its thing.
青蛙有不可思议的生存能力
This is a frog that has incredible staying power.
青蛙能很神奇地适应恶劣的环境
They're incredibly well adapted to this harsh environment.
现在 我们只能眼睁睁地看着青蛙死掉
And now, on our watch, they're disappearing.
小组忙着收集尽可能多的数据
Argo: the team is rushing to collect as much data as they can,
但是壶菌是令人迷惑的敌人
But chytrid is a puzzling enemy.
虽然有些物种对壶菌有抵抗力
While some species appear to be resistant,
其他物种却被毁灭
Others are being devastated.
黄腿山蛙的死亡速度很快
The mountain yellow-legged frog is losing ground fast.
好的 57.
All right, 57.
引起壶菌病的真菌 简称BD
The fungus that causes chytrid, known as "BD,"
几个月内就可以感染 并致死所有的青蛙
Can extinguish a population in a matter of months.
壶菌好像在高海拔的地区繁殖
It seems to thrive at high altitudes,
这些地区阴凉潮湿
Where it's cool and moist,
但是没人知道壶菌怎样蔓延 怎样才能阻止它
But no one knows how it travels, or how to stop it.
壶菌病正在山脉地区蔓延
The disease is sweeping through the sierras,
在墨西哥 壶菌病被确认
It's well established in mexico,
壶菌病蔓延至中美洲和南美洲
And it's been moving through central and south america,
毁灭沿途的两栖动物
Devastating amphibians.
中美洲和南美洲
Woman: central and south america
生活了全球50%的两栖物种
Harbored 50% of the world's amphibian species.
这些地区拥有最多的两栖物种
This was the place with the greatest amount,
现在可能大部分都灭绝了
And now we've potentially lost a huge portion of that.
在哥斯达黎加 Karen Lips博士
Argo: in costa rica, Dr.Karen Lips
首次亲眼看到 青蛙的神秘死亡
Was one of the first to witness a mysterious die-off of frogs.
有一天 我走过小溪 发现一只死蛙
Lips: one day I was walking down the stream, and I found a dead frog,
我有点担心
And, you know, I was a little concerned,
但是在接下来几个星期 我又发现了几只死蛙
But...over the next couple of weeks I found a couple more.
我下一年回来时 青蛙都不见了
I went back the next year, and they were gone.
青蛙不见了
The frogs had disappeared.
其实 同样的事情
Essentially the same story played out
也发生在几年后的巴拿马边境
A couple of years later across the border in panama.
Lips博士在中美洲看到死蛙的时候
Argo: while Lips was witnessing die-offs in central america,
同样的一幕也在澳大利亚上演
A similar story played out in australia.
直到确认了壶菌病
By the time chytrid was identified,
全世界的两栖动物已经崩溃了
Amphibian populations had already crashed throughout the world.
壶菌已经偷偷地进入
The fungus has been stealthy,
那些没开发 但又拥有地球上最珍稀物种的区域
Reaching into untouched areas that hold some of earth's greatest treasures.
青蛙可能是渺小的
Frogs might be diminutive,
后果却是严重的
But the stakes are enormous.
医学已经证实 青蛙是小金矿
Medical science has begun to realize that frogs are little gold mines.
为了应对感染 很多青蛙的皮肤能够分泌化学物
To ward off infection, most frogs secrete chemicals from their skin.
有时青蛙甚至是有毒的
They can actually be poisonous.
这些明亮的颜色警告掠食者
These bright colors are a frog's warning to predators
青蛙是危险的食物
That they could be a dangerous meal.
青蛙皮肤上的化合物 已经使医学重现生机
The compounds on frog skin have turned medical science around.
从小青蛙皮肤提取的化合物
An extract from the skin of this little frog blocks pain
止痛的效果比吗啡好 而且不会令人上瘾
More effectively than morphine -- and it's not addictive.
青蛙皮肤的性质 可应用到各个领域
The properties of frog skin are being explored for everything
例如治疗感染和防止艾滋病
From treating infections to preventing HIV.
我们才刚开始挖掘这个小宝藏
We've just begun to mine these little treasures,
现在青蛙却衰减了 速度比我们的研究速度快得多
And now they're slipping away faster than we can study them.
但是这对全球生态系统的影响更大
But the impact on earth's ecosystems is even more troubling.
Karen Lips博士回到位于巴拿马中部的 前研究基地
Karen Lips has returned to her former study site
她要测量这些地区的变化
In central panama to measure the changes.
没有青蛙 这里静得可怕
Without the frogs, there's an eerie silence.
在El Cope保护区
In El Cope reserve,
只剩下一座水泥青蛙雕塑
A concrete statue may be all that remains
记录了巴拿马引人入胜的金蛙
Of panama's spectacular golden frog.
青蛙大灭绝之前 这里是个好地方
Lips: before the big crash, this was a great place.
我估计这里大概有 64种两栖动物
I think our total list here was something like 64 species of amphibians.
无论你走到森林的哪个地方
It didn't matter really where you went in the forest,
你都能找到青蛙 地面上、叶子上
You would find them on the ground, on the leaves,
你能听见青蛙在树冠上
You'd hear them up in the canopy.
无论你走过哪条小径和溪流
You could walk any trail, any stream,
你都能听到青蛙日夜叫个不停
And you would hear frogs calling day and night.
现在 这里一个青蛙也没有了
And now, you know, there's just nothing here anymore.
壶菌病具有多米诺效应
Argo: chytrid is having a domino effect.
青蛙位于食物链的中部
Frogs sit right in the middle of the food chain.
没有青蛙 其它物种也会灭绝
Without them, other creatures are disappearing, too.
我们才刚开始了解 没有青蛙
Lips: we're just beginning to understand what a forest is like
森林会如何运作、变成啥样
And how it functions without frogs.
现在所有的蝌蚪都死掉了
Ever since all the tadpoles disappeared,
这些小溪真的很滑
These streams have been really slippery.
地面长满了绿藻
There's green algae growing all over the place.
这是青蛙和蝌蚪灭绝后
It's just another example of the big changes that we see
发生的巨大变化的一个例子
After all the frogs and tadpoles disappear.
蝌蚪不仅吃绿藻
The tadpoles not only eat the algae,
蝌蚪还会扰动沙泥
But they also disturb all the sand and the mud,
因此沙泥附着物被水流带走
And so all that gets flushed out with the current --
现在这里没有蝌蚪了
And now there's no tadpoles,
我们看到昆虫也有变化
We see changes in some of the insects, as well.
这里的生态系统变化很大
We're seeing lots of big changes in these ecosystems.
青蛙灭绝影响到鱼类、水质 蛇类、鸟类........ 你来想吧
It's affecting fish, and water quality, snakes, birds -- you name it.
基本上 我们观测到的一切都改变了
Basically everything we've measured has changed.
壶菌病正在蔓延
Argo: chytrid is on the move.
壶菌病从中美洲向北蔓延
While it's sweeping down through central america,
壶菌病也从南美洲向北蔓延
It's also traveling north from south america.
只有巴拿马的一个小地方
There's only a small area left in panama
至今没有受到壶菌感染
That still seems to be chytrid-free.
巴拿马运河以北 两小时的路程
Two hours south of the panama canal,
有一叫做Burbayar的小森林
There's a small patch of forest called Burbayar.
这里的青蛙 依然按照几百万年以来 形成的方式生活
For the frogs here, life plays out as it has for millions of years.
壶菌逐渐逼近 奇迹有待出现
While chytrid draws closer, miracles are still unfolding.
老爸已经守卫孩子两个多星期了
This father has been guarding his young for two weeks now.
附近叶子上的蝌蚪却没有护卫
The tadpoles on a nearby leaf don't have a guardian.
这些蝌蚪较成熟 但仍然需要几天时间才能孵化
They're more mature, but still days from hatching.
健康的栖息地 有许多掠食者和食物
A healthy habitat is full of predators -- and prey.
无论大小 每种生物都扮演着自己的角色
No matter how big or small, every creature plays a role.
森林拥有数以千计的昆虫种类
The forest holds thousands of insect species.
有些昆虫几个小时就毁掉一窝蛙卵
Some can destroy an egg clutch in a matter of hours...
即使入侵者还没触及卵窝
Even if an intruder doesn't have a taste for eggs,
这个老爸依然奋勇保护
This father is fiercely protective.
虽然有些物种不保护孩子
Though the other species doesn't guard its young,
孩子已经具备另一种防卫术
It's developed another defense --
面对攻击 蝌蚪会努力挣扎开来
When attacked, the tadpoles will break free,
使蝌蚪至少有斗争的机会
Giving them at least a fighting chance.
在这里的溪流
Here in the stream,
蝌蚪花很多时间 吃绿藻和小植物
The tadpoles will spend most of their time feeding on algae and small plants.
一系列迷人的生存技能 使青蛙勇敢生存了几百万年
A fantastic array of survival tactics has allowed frogs to brave the millennia.
但是 壶菌与其它任何掠食者都不同
But chytrid is a predator like none other --
壶菌蔓延很快
And it's moving in fast.
时间紧迫
Lips: the clock is ticking --
自从92年这里第一只青蛙死掉后
And that's really what it's felt like more than anything
我们真正需要的是速度
Since that first frog in '92, is the rush --
在壶菌感染之前 尽快地救出尽可能多的青蛙
The rush to get out, to do as much as you can before another site goes.
Lips和她的学生们
Argo: Lips and her students
在Burbayar森林建立了 一个新的研究基地
Have established a new study site here at Burbayar.
他们希望 壶菌病还没有蔓延到这里
They're hoping that chytrid, and the BD that causes it, haven't arrived yet.
我们在这里试图获取更多的数据
Lips: we're here to try and get more data to figure out
以确认发生了什么事 壶菌病是怎样来到的?
What is happening -- how does this thing get around?
我们可以阻止壶菌病吗?
Can we stop it?
森林里有青蛙、昆虫和蛇 看上去很健康
Argo: the forest appears to be healthy, with frogs, and insects, and snakes...
但这种情形还能维持多久呢?
But for how much longer will it remain intact?
使青蛙健康生活的栖息地 远远不够了
Lips: we're running out of places where frogs are healthy.
我们估计 十年后巴拿马所有的青蛙都会灭绝
We estimate, within ten years all of panama will be gone.
我指的是高海拔地区
We're talking upland areas,
但是就算你走得快 壶菌病也持续蔓延
But as fast as you move, it's continuing its passage.
我抓到一个青蛙
Woman: I got a frog.
一旦我们抓到青蛙 我们就测量青蛙的体温
As soon as we catch a frog, we take its body temperature,
因为在气候变化及其对青蛙的影响方面 存在争议
Because there's a debate about climate change and how it's affecting frogs.
33.5℃.
33.5度
接着我们用棉签檫拭青蛙
Next we're going to swab it,
并把棉签样品送回实验室 检测可以告诉我们
And we'll send this sample off to a lab, and they'll tell us
这个青蛙是否感染了壶菌
Whether or not this frog is infected with BD.
好的 现在我们抓住小腿
All right, so we're just going to take this little q-tip
檫拭青蛙皮肤
And swab the frog.
我们檫拭青蛙的腹部和腿
We do his belly, we do his feet.
如果上面有壶菌 棉签会沾上它 我们带回实验室
If there's any BD, it'll pick it up, and we send this off to the lab,
检测结果会表明 这是青蛙是否感染了壶菌
And the lab will tell us if BD is on this frog.
好的 你走吧 伙计
All right, i'm gonna let you go, buddy.
我们认为这个地方还算健康
Lips: we think this site is still clean.
快看
Look at that --
这是Rhinobothryum Bovallii蛇
That's Rhinobothryum Bovallii.
非常罕见
They're really rare.
这条好大
That's a big one.
它以青蛙为食
They're a frog-eater.
它正出来找吃的 你看它舌头轻吐
He's out foraging, you can see him tongue-flicking.
一旦壶菌驾到 此蛇也可能和青蛙一样灭绝
Argo: once chytrid arrives, this snake may well disappear along with the frogs.
基于Lips博士的研究结果 他们要采取紧急措施
Based on what Lips finds here, they might take emergency measures.
如果有必要 我们会把青蛙放到
Lips: if we have to, we will put some frogs
囚禁地加以保护 以应对壶菌的最终到来
Into captivity as a safeguard against the eventual arrival of the fungus.
三年前 生物学家在中美洲就是这样做的
Argo: this is exactly what took place in central panama, three years ago.
壶菌病逐渐逼近
With chytrid fast approaching,
生物学家从周围的森林中收集青蛙
Biologists evacuated frogs from the surrounding forest.
这些“难民"离雾林是如此的近
These refugees are so close...
却又是如此的远
And yet so far from their cloud forest.
山脚有一栋简陋的建筑 作为庇护所
At the foot of the mountains sits a humble building that's serving as an ark.
El Valle两栖动物保护中心（EVACC）
The El Valle amphibian conservation center
是休斯顿动物园发起的国际计划
Is an international project launched by the houston zoo.
EVACC保护了58种青蛙
"EVACC" shelters 58 species of frogs --
有些是地球上的稀有种类
Some of the rarest on earth.
这个美丽的金蛙是 巴拿马的独有品种
This beautiful golden frog is unique to panama.
金蛙没有耳膜 通过摆臂交流
It lacks eardrums, and communicates by waving its arms.
巴拿马人认为金蛙是好运
They're considered good luck by panamanians,
但是 金蛙可能会因为壶菌而灭绝
But because of chytrid, they may be gone from the wild.
Edgardo Griffith和他的妻子Heidi Rs共同管理这个中心
Edgardo Griffith runs the center with his wife, Heidi Rs.
他们要模拟雾林
They have to try to replicate the cloud forest --
光线、温度、湿度 所有条件都有适当
Light, temperature, humidity -- everything has to be right.
要喂食很多个月 这是没完没了的挑战
And feeding so many mouths is a never-ending challenge.
我刚刚漂洗了蚯蚓 因为它们身上可能有壶菌
We just rinse them off, just because the worms might have chytrid on them.
不经过消毒 我们不会把任何东西 如灰尘
We try not to put anything, like dirt, without disinfecting it
放进这间屋子
Before putting it inside the building.
进入EVACC的所有东西都要 保证无壶菌
Argo: everything entering EVACC has to be chytrid-free --
每个人 每条虫 每块石头 每种植物
Every person, every worm, every rock and plant.
这些角形树蛙 与森林的树叶相似
These horned tree frogs mimic leaves in the forest.
即使小蛙也伪装得很好
Even the froglets are brilliantly disguised.
但是最好的伪装 也挡不住壶菌
But the best of camouflage can't protect a frog from chytrid.
在隔离区
In the quarantine room,
新来的青蛙 都要经过严格的消毒程序
New arrivals are put through a grueling process.
我们现在还不知道 怎样清除栖息地的壶菌
We don't yet know how to rid a habitat of chytrid,
但是我们能应对青蛙个体
But individual frogs can be treated.
没事 朋友 没事
It's okay, my friend, it's okay.
没事
It's okay.
看看你
Look at you.
我们从2006年开始收集青蛙
When we started collecting the animals in 2006,
50%的都死掉了
We lost like 50% of them.
这些青蛙能活很多年
These frogs can live for years --
可能有20或25年
Probably 20, 25 years.
就像接受化学治疗的人类一样
The treatment equivalent would be for a person going under chemotherapy.
我让它在那里呆10分钟
I'll leave it there for 10 minutes.
这是侵略性的治疗
It's a very invasive process,
因为我们必须使青蛙和溶液接触
Because we have to keep the frogs in contact
溶液真的很强烈
With this solution, which is a really strong solution,
每天治疗10分钟 总共要10天
For ten minutes for ten days.
我确信它不想呆在杯子
I'm pretty sure that she doesn't like to be
它要和令人厌恶的溶液接触
In that little cup with that nasty solution,
但是 事实表明
But there's something that tells me
它知道我们在帮助它
That she knows somehow that we are trying to help her.
很多人认为这不重要
For most people, they wouldn't think that this is important,
因为它只是一个棕色、凹凸不平的小丑蛙
Because it's a brown, bumpy, little ugly frog,
但是它正在告诉我们 人类正在做错事
But this animal here is telling us that we are doing something wrong.
在EVACC 能看到产卵和蝌蚪就算成功了
Argo: at EVACC, success is measured by egg clutches and tadpoles.
最近 小组庆祝了 一只小金蛙首次变态成成体蛙
They recently celebrated the first golden froglet to metamorphose.
但也有不可避免的失败
But there are also the inevitable setbacks.
在这里
It's over here.
这是中心最早拯救的青蛙之一
This was one of the center's first rescues.
总有一些寄生虫之类的出现
There's always parasites and such lined up,
等等 这是第一次出错
Just waiting -- so the first mistake,
这表明我们做得不对
It will show us that we're not doing things right.
一旦寄生虫出现症状 通常是时间 太晚了
Once they present the symptoms, it's oftentimes too late.
看到了吗?
See this?
噢 我的天
Oh, my gosh!
有一大片寄生虫 寄生虫在内部
There's a gigantic parasite that was internal.
当宿主死掉后 寄生虫就来了
When the host died, i'm sure the parasite came over.
青蛙 我们知之甚少
So many things that we don't know about these animals,
有许多新寄生虫
So many new species of parasites.
发生这样的事 我们很不适应
We can never get used to things like this happening.
最终目标是 某天把青蛙放回野外
Argo: the ultimate goal is to return these frogs to the wild someday.
科学家正在寻找控制壶菌的方法
Scientists are working to find ways to control chytrid in the environment.
迄今 控制方法还是一个遥遥无期的梦想
But for now, it's still a distant dream.
El Valle变化很快
And things in El Valle are changing quickly.
房地产开发可能会重新改写 巴拿马青蛙的未来
Housing developments might be re-writing the future for panama's frogs.
他们正在开发这个地区
Griffith: they're developing this area.
去年我在这里迷路了
Last year I came this way, and I got lost.
这里有很多新公路 所以我不知道该往哪里走
There are so many new roads here that I didn't even know where I was going anymore.
至少一年前 只有这样的一条公路
Less than a year ago, there was only one road.
两年前 当我们开始EVACC项目的时候
Two years ago, when we started the EVACC project,
我们来到这里收集青蛙 就是在这个地方
We came here and we collected some frogs from this particular place,
不到1年 开发商就完全占领了这里
And in less than a year, they cleared the whole thing.
这可能是某人的房子
This is going to be somebody's house.
我非常震惊
I feel just panic,
因为我以前看到那里有很多森林
Because when I look up that way, there's a lot of forest,
这里发生的事情 不到1年 也会发生在那些森林
But the same thing that happened here can happen to that forest in less than a year.
中心里很多的安全、健康的青蛙都不重要了
It doesn't matter now many safe, healthy frogs we have at the center --
如果栖息地继续丧失
If habitat loss continues,
将来我们要把青蛙放回哪里呢
Where are we going to put the frogs in the future,
如果我们找出挽救青蛙的方法 使青蛙在野外对抗真菌
If we figure out how to help them so they can fight the fungus in the wild?
再也没有青蛙的栖息地了
There's not going to be a place for the frogs anymore.
还有一线希望 有些青蛙可以抵抗壶菌
Argo: there is hope that a few individual frogs might be resistant to chytrid,
但是房地产开发产生的废物 使溪流不适合青蛙生存了
But runoff from the development is making the stream unhealthy for frogs.
我永不放弃
Griffith: I will never give up.
我一有机会就会过来
I will still come every time when I have the opportunity,
因为我们总有可能找到青蛙
Because there is always the possibility for us to find frogs.
这些事情
That's one of the things that,
你每天早上都会想
You know, every morning you think about.
壶菌的破坏能力强
Argo: chytrid has been devastating,
但壶菌病并不是两栖动物的 唯一威胁
But it's by no means the only threat to amphibians.
在美国一些没被壶菌感染的地区
In parts of the u.s. Where frogs haven't been lost to the fungus,
青蛙受到其它力量的冲击
They're being hit by other forces,
这就发生在我们的后院
Right here in our own backyards.
13年前 在明尼苏达州
In minnesota, 13 years ago,
一群学生边旅行边寻找青蛙
A group of school kids took a field trip to look for frogs.
学生找到很多可怕的青蛙
What they found was the stuff of nightmares...
这些青蛙要么多长了一条腿 要么缺了一条腿
They found frogs with extra limbs, missing limbs,
这些畸形青蛙就是大自然的反面教材
Deformities at seemed to defy nature.
美国其它地方也有相似的报道
Similar reports began to surface from around the country,
这敲响了警钟
Sounding an alarm.
在耶鲁大学
At yale university,
David Skelly博士及其学生
Dr.David Skelly and his students
8年来都在收集畸形的青蛙
Have been collecting deformed frogs for the past eight years.
他们的研究结果有非凡的意义
Their findings have disturbing implications --
无论是对青蛙 还是对人类而言
For frogs and humans alike.
科学家发现 有一种寄生虫会导致多腿
Scientists have discovered that a kind of parasite can cause multiple limbs --
但Skelly博士关心其他的青蛙畸形 这些畸形还无法解析
But Skelly is concerned about other deformities that have yet to be explained.
这是豹蛙
Skelly: this is a leopard frog,
它感染了Ribeiroia吸虫就变成这样子
And this is what happens when they're infected with a parasite called Ribeiroia.
这是导致自然界肢体畸形的一个原因
This is one of the causes for limb deformities in the natural world.
虽然多腿动物受到很大的关注
While the animals with the extra legs get a lot of attention,
这才是我真正关心的
This is the animal that really concerns me --
这是一只变态前的豹蛙
This is a leopard frog metamorph,
只有一条隐形腿
As well, and it's got only one hind limb.
这是蛙尾
This is the animal's tail here.
这些动物至关重要
What makes these animals so significant is
因为我们不知道造成畸形的原因
We really don't know what causes these kinds of deformities.
在收集青蛙的地方 没发现寄生虫
The parasite is not found where this frog was collected.
所以畸形与寄生虫无关
So that can't be what's going on here.
是其它原因造成的 我们还不清楚
It's got to be something else, and we don't know what it is.
Skelly博士希望在其它地方找到答案
Argo: Skelly has been looking for answers in some unlikely places.
这里是康涅狄格的郊区
Here in suburban connecticut,
Skelly博士发现这里的动物生活 并不像大家想的那样隐蔽
He's finding that life might not be as sheltered as folks once thought.
普通居民都可能加速青蛙的灭亡
The average resident might be hastening the demise of frogs,
就像居民危害自己的健康一样
While they undermine their own health.
我们几年前就来这个池塘取样本
Skelly: we started sampling this pond a few years ago,
发现有一些畸形青蛙繁殖
And we're finding reproductive deformities in the frogs.
那里有一只
There's another one.
像这样的郊区池塘
In suburban ponds like this,
我们发现21%的青蛙都是畸形的
We're finding that about 21% of all the frogs have deformities -- that is,
例如雄蛙会产卵
Male frogs are growing eggs inside their testes.
十分不正常
And that is not normal at all.
布满池塘的浮萍
Argo: the duckweed that's choking this pond
可能是化学品造成的 例如肥料
Is probably caused by chemicals like fertilizers.
但Skelly博士也关心 其它一些不明显的化合物
But Skelly is also concerned about compounds that are less conspicuous.
我们很多人没有认识到
Skelly: I think a lot of people don't realize
使用化学品时
That when they use chemicals,
或者把药丸冲下马桶
Or if they flush medications down their toilet,
这些物质会流出房子
That it could end up passing right out of the house,
经过特殊的管道 流入池塘
Right through a septic field, and right into a pond.
很多人都没注意到这些
It's just not something people have thought about --
同样 科学家、监督人和决策人
And to be fair, it's not something that scientists and regulators and policy makers
也很少注意到这些
Have thought about very much, either.
流进池塘的水 含有像药丸这样的东西
All of that water collects in these basins. Things like medications.
大家吃很多各种各样的药丸
There are a huge range of drugs that people take,
很多药丸对人体无害
And many of them leave our bodies intact.
举个例子 最明显的药丸 避孕药
We're starting with the most obvious candidate -- birth control pills.
实验发现 合成的雌激素
We know in the laboratory that synthetic estrogen
会导致这种后果
Can cause these kinds of problems.
现在我们要知道
Now we just need to figure out
这个地方是否也在发生同样的事情
If that is what's going on in places like this.
和Skelly博士一样 在加州大学伯克利分校的Tyrone Hayes博士也认同这样的警告
Argo: Skelly's alarm is shared by Dr.Tyrone Hayes at u.c. Berkeley.
如果整个种族的青蛙
Hayes: if an entire class of animals
已经在生存了几百万年
That's been around for millions and millions of years
如果青蛙数量正在下降 并面临灭绝的潜在危险
Is rapidly declining and potentially going extinct,
我们真的需要想想 我们做过的事情
We really need to think about what we've done,
我们的行为最终会危害自己
And if our advances will eventually harm us all.
我非常热爱科学
I really like the science.
我喜欢解决问题 我喜欢看”犯罪现场“
I like solving the puzzle, I like the CSI.
我也喜欢青蛙
I also like frogs,
所以我有兴趣搞研究 帮助大家了解
And so I also feel a real drive to help understand
杀虫剂及其它的化学品 是如何影响两栖动物的
How pesticides and other chemicals are affecting amphibian populations.
Hayes博士和他的学生
Argo: Hayes and his students
在沙林纳斯谷寻找线索
Have been looking for clues in the salinas valley.
50%的美国农产品 来自加利福尼亚州
Hayes: 50% of the u.s.'s agricultural products come out of california.
大约85%的生菜 来自于沙林纳斯谷
And something like 85% of the country's lettuce comes out of salinas.
这里还生产90%的杏仁
90% of the almonds.
沙林纳斯谷是美国人的色拉盘
It's called the salad bowl of america.
加利福尼亚州使用的杀虫剂比其他州多
California uses more pesticides than any other state.
排名第二的是佛罗里达州
The second biggest is florida.
像三氯硝基甲之类的杀虫剂 被用在这里的草莓地
Things like chloropicrin is used out here on the strawberries --
三氯硝基甲是一种神经气体
Chloropicrin is a nerve gas.
这里的人正在使用它 青蛙在外面会吸收它
These are the guys who are applying it, they're out there picking it.
溴化甲烷是一种薰剂
Methyl bromide is a fumigant,
人们把薰剂泵入土壤
Something they pump into the soil.
伙计 这个大家伙是什么?
What are some of the other big ones, you guys?
二嗪农 还有阿特拉津（除草剂）
Diazinol... Some atrazine...
所有这些化合物都会流进河里 就像这条河
This will all end up in the river that we're working in here.
就像我们来到某处灌木
It might look like we're out in the bush somewhere,
但是两边15尺开外就是农田
But 15 feet on either side, we're surrounded by agriculture,
废物都跑进河里了
And the runoff ends up in this river.
藻类就是养分充沛的结果
All the algae is the result of all the nutrients,
因为农田需要很多肥料
Because a lot of fertilizers are used in agriculture,
一旦肥料进入水里面 藻类就繁荣生长了
And once those fertilizers get into the water, you get these blooms of algae.
我认为 藻类不是河水清洁的证明
I wouldn't say it's the sign of a healthy river.
这种地方 我们通常能找到有害的免疫系统
This is a site where we typically find compromised immune systems --
蝌蚪无法应对疾病
Tadpoles that aren't able to fight off disease.
我们的研究表明
Our data so far suggests that
杀虫剂导致压力荷尔蒙的增加
The mixture of pesticides causes an increase in stress hormones,
这些压力荷尔蒙引起抑制免疫反应
And those stress hormones cause immunosuppression,
最终导致生物无法应对任何一种的病原体
Which leads to the inability to respond to any kind of disease pathogen.
在研究化学废水的同时 Hayes也盯上了另外一个元凶
Argo: while investigating chemical runoff, Hayes stumbled on another culprit.
我们来到萨利纳斯河
Hayes: we started going to the salinas river
寻找红腿的本地蛙
Looking for the native red-legged frog,
我们发现红腿蛙完全被牛蛙取代
And it turns out that it has been completely replaced on the river by bullfrogs.
这种具有侵略性的牛蛙
This invasive bullfrog itself
其数量也在减少 当地人是其中一个原因
Is one of the causes for decline in man of these areas.
所以我们研究牛蛙
And so we're studying them
牛蛙在这里过得并不好
In areas where they're not doing well
我们试图了解 造成本地红腿蛙灭绝的原因
To try to understand what may be driving some of the native species to extinction.
企业家从东海岸把牛蛙运来这里
Argo: entrepreneurs transported bullfrogs from the east coast,
希望养殖牛蛙 作为人类的食物
Hoping to farm them for food.
然而 企业家却放出了这种肉食动物
Instead, they unleashed a carnivore
牛蛙已经毁掉了加利福尼亚的本地蛙
That has decimated california's native frogs.
即使强壮的牛蛙 也不能适应河水里的毒物
It seems that even the tough bullfrog isn't doing so well with the toxins in this water.
回到实验室 Hayes研究另外一种非本地蛙
Back at berkeley, Hayes is studying another non-native.
非洲爪蛙一度用于人类的妊娠试验
African clawed frogs were once used in human pregnancy tests.
当瓜蛙变得无用时 就被抛弃了
But when they became obsolete, many were discarded.
这些瓜蛙来自加利福尼亚附近的水流
These were collected from streams around california.
我们切开一只瓜蛙
Hayes: we're removing an invasive frog,
通过研究瓜蛙 来了解两栖动物数量下降的原因
And we're studying them to try to understand declining amphibians.
Hayes研究化学品的影响
Hayes is testing the effects of chemicals
阿特拉津 一种普通的除草剂
Like atrazine, a common herbicide.
这些动物 我们都切除了雌性染色体
Hayes: we have a whole family of animals where we've eliminated the female chromosome.
01号标本
Woman: specimen zero-one.
这些在基因上 都是雄性动物
Hayes: these animals that we know are genetic males
我们把这些动物 一直和阿特拉津接触
Have been exposed to atrazine for their entire life,
很多这些基因上的雄性动物
And many of these genetic males
现在都变成雌性动物了
Now are turning into females.
你可以看到 他会产卵
You can see he's got eggs
看上去好像是液囊
That kind of look like they're in a sac.
其实是黄色的卵 而且快要产下来了
These are actually yolked eggs, ready to be laid.
我们可以改变性别比例
What's happening is you're skewing sex ratios,
你可以打破基因瓶颈
You can get genetic bottlenecking,
这会造成毁坏 坦白说
Which can cause crashes, and quite frankly,
如果你在基因上是男的
If you're a genetic male,
长大后变成男人 这非常好
It would be nice if you developed as a genetic male,
现在我们有一种存在环境中的 很普通的化学品
And now we have a chemical very common in the environment,
可以有效地改变动物的性别
That's effectively sex-reversing animals.
我要向你展示 令人惊奇的情景
I'm going to show you something pretty amazing,
科学而言
Scientifically speaking.
值得注意的是这一对
The one that's sort of remarkable is this pair.
它们都是雄性动物
These are both males.
底部的那个变成雌性动物
The one on the bottom acting as the female
我们动情地叫它"Darnell."
We affectionately refer to as "Darnell."
他的基因是雄性的 却不仅在行动上像雌性
He's a genetic male that not only acts like a female,
他还会像雌性那样产卵
He lays eggs like a female.
他/她一生都暴露于阿特拉津杀虫剂
He/she has been exposed to atrazine all of her -- his/her life --
我不知道怎样称呼它
I don't even really know how to reference it.
这是“Darnell”第三次产卵
This is Darnell's third clutch.
所以Darnell有男女后代 我们已经把这些后代养大
So Darnell has sons and daughters that we've grown up.
你可以看看底部的卵
You can see eggs in the bottom.
其实这是他今天的第二次卵了
This is actually her second clutch for today.
他/她交配已经超过24小时
He/she has been copulating for getting close to 24 hours now.
这可能是我研究中 看到的最引入注目的事情
This is probably one of the most remarkable things i've seen in my work,
但我的心情很复杂
But I personally have mixed emotions.
我对科学着迷
I'm very excited about the science
我试图了解变性机理 但另一方面
And trying to understand the mechanism, but on the other hand,
我又非常担心 这种污染物非常普遍
I am worried -- this is the most common contaminant
地下水、地面水和饮用水中都有
In ground and surface water, and drinking water,
使动物变性的阿特拉津的 浓度水平
And the level of atrazine that it took to make this male turn into a female
只有我们饮用水的 规定值的三分之一
Is three times less than what's allowed in our drinking water.
我认为全球两栖动物数量下降
I really think that the global amphibian decline
正在暗示人类的健康问题
Is telling us something about human health.
人类用水中的毒物水平远远高于青蛙
Argo: the toxins in our waters are reaching well beyond frogs.
畸形繁殖的报道常常见于
Reproductive abnormalities have been reported in everything from
鳄鱼、北极熊 以及人类
Alligators to polar bears... To humans.
这并不只是青蛙的事情
Hayes: it's not just a problem with frogs
我们也应该关注
We should be concerned about.
造成青蛙畸形的水
The water that's causing their problems
人类也在饮用同样的水
Is the same water that we're drinking
并用同样的水来灌溉农作物
And using to water our crops.
无论是青蛙还是人类
Argo: frog or human,
我们都呼吸同样的空气 饮用同样的水
We all breathe the same air and drink the same water.
为了青蛙和人类的利益 专家一致认为
For their sake and ours, experts agree --
我们必须行动起来 没有时间了
We have to take action, and there's no time to lose.
澳大利亚受致命的壶菌的打击最大
Australia has been hard hit by the deadly fungus, chytrid.
7种两栖动物灭绝了
Seven species have been lost,
更多的物种正在面临相同的命运
And more are on a fast track to extinction.
现在 气候变化 火上加油
Now, add climate change to the mix.
澳大利亚受干旱影响 史无前例
Australia is experiencing its worst drought on record --
两栖动物也受到打击
And amphibians are feeling it.
南部的布罗雨滨蛙
In the south, a population of booroolong frogs
在河干时全部死掉了
Was evacuated when their river dried up.
Gerry Marantelli一直养殖青蛙来应对气候变化
Gerry Marantelli has been breeding the frogs to hedge against climate change.
这里有些不错的卵 Erika.
Marantelli: we have some good eggs here, Erika.
很新鲜 不错
These are fresh, but they're good.
一些新卵
Some new ones.
在墨尔本市的郊区 Marantelli和他的爱妻Erika,
Argo: just outside of melbourne, Marantelli and his wife, Erika,
建立了一个不寻常的庇护所
Have created an unusual ark.
开始时我们买不起房子
Marantelli: we couldn't afford buildings when we started.
怎么办呢？
We thought, "what do we do?"
我们买来轮船的集装箱
We bought shipping containers.
像这样的集装箱 可防水、隔热
Shipping containers like this are waterproof and insulated,
把集装箱改装成完美的青蛙实验室
And we can convert them into a perfectly useful lab for these frogs,
安装灌溉系统
Installing irrigation systems --
所有青蛙需要的东东
All the things that the frogs need --
价钱不多
But they're a fraction of the price.
集装箱是便携式的 可以拆开
And to top it off, they're portable,
所以青蛙需要帮助时 我们可以把它们运到世界的任何地方
So we can ship them anywhere in the world where frogs need help.
庇护所里面有澳大利亚 频临灭绝的青蛙
Argo: here at the ark are australia's most endangered frogs --
布罗雨滨蛙
The booroolong frog,
斑纹树蛙
The spotted tree frog,
还有引入注目的澳洲夜宴蛙
And the extraordinary corroboree.
名字来自土著语
Its name is an aboriginal word
意思是"庆祝"或"聚会"
For "celebration" or "gathering,"
庆祝时 老者常常涂上黑黄相间的颜料
Where the elders often wear black and yellow paint.
澳洲夜宴蛙 一度繁荣昌盛
Corroborees used to be plentiful,
但是壶菌把它们 逼到生存的边缘
But chytrid has pushed them to the edge.
谈到把青蛙放回野外 Marantelli夫妇异常激动
The Marantellis are vehement about returning frogs to the wild.
尽快搞清楚这个难题 解决它
Marantelli: the quicker we can understand the problems they face, fix the problems,
把青蛙放回野外 越快越好
And get these frogs back into the wild, the better.
青蛙不能100年都生活在鱼柜里
They can't live in a fish tank for 100 years --
我们毁掉了吃青蛙的动物
We disrupt the things that eat the frogs,
以及青蛙吃的动物
The things that the frogs eat.
它们都是生态系统的一部分
They are part of an ecosystem,
这个集装箱不是生态系统
And this tank is not an ecosystem.
这些小青蛙奔向溪流
Argo: these little frogs are headed back to their stream.
干旱终于过去了
The drought has finally broken...
至少现在过去了
At least for now.
这是澳洲夜宴蛙 来自Boorooree河
Marantelli: these are booroolong frogs from Boorooree creek.
随着气候的变化
With climate change,
在上次干旱季节 Boorooree的河流变干了
Boorooree creek dried up in the last drought,
所以我们必须囚禁并养育它们
So we had to bring them into captivity and breed them,
这些比较年轻
And these are all the young ones
我们把它们放回Boorooree河
That we're taking back to Boorooree creek.
我们大概放回500个青蛙
We've got a little bit over 500 frogs to go back.
明天你们会回到Boorooree河
You'll be back to Boorooree creek tomorrow.
兴奋吗? 快看!
Are you excited? Look at that!
看上去很兴奋!
You look excited!
澳洲夜宴蛙还遭遇
With the booroolong frog,
气候变暖 和更长久的干旱
Climate change -- warming conditions and the prolonged drought,
所有这些都汇合在一起 使溪流停止流动
All of that sort of came together and made the stream stop flowing.
栖息地正在改变 这意味着环境有些不对劲
The fact that those habitats are changing right now means something is going wrong,
也意味着我们要行动起来 来帮助这些小伙计
And that means we've got to do something about helping the little guys.
快看!
Look at that!
你想看澳洲夜宴蛙吗?
You want to see some booroolong frogs?
看吧
Have a look.
你知道他们是谁? 你们的新朋友
You know what they are? There's your new friends.
今晚好好聆听
You listen to them tonight.
Marantelli留了些青蛙在实验中心
Argo: Marantelli has kept some frogs back at the center as a safeguard.
作为气候变化的保护者 它们还需要帮助
With climate change, they might need help again.
快看 欢迎回家!
Look at that -- welcome home!
他们下午放了一些小蛙
They release some of the froglets in the afternoon light;
小蛙会和其它动物分享这条河
They'll share the rest with the locals.
不要上那里 鸟会吃了你
Not up there -- a bird will eat you.
走吧 找个小裂缝 回家吧
Go and find a little crevice. Go home.
噢 快看 肥仔 快走啊!
Oh, look at this fat one, harry!
孩子们看青蛙时 我很开心
Marantelli: I love it when kids are looking at frogs.
那里有一只大肥蛙
There, that's a huge fat one.
我们要做的是 喂它们
That's what we do, we feed them
好多、好多的蟋蟀
Lots and lots and lots of crickets --
你一生中都没有看过这么多的蟋蟀
More crickets than you've ever seen in your life.
如果孩子们不感兴趣
If they're not interested,
50年后这个计划就会破产
Then the project falls apart in 50 years.
确信社区的人都行动起来 这非常重要
It's really important to make sure the community's on board,
特别是周围有青蛙的社区
Particularly where the community lives amongst the frogs.
调动大家 带大家到野外
Tip everything up and tip them out.
让他们看看青蛙的栖息地
They're out there watching the habitat,
他们会照顾这些溪流
And they'll look after those creeks
现在澳洲夜宴蛙回来了
Now that the booroolong frogs are back.
我们就像桥梁 帮助这些青蛙度过难关
We're just a bridge across a bump -- for all of these frogs --
为了帮助青蛙 不管需要1年 还是10年
Whether it takes us a year to help them out, or ten years,
还是20年 我们都会一如既往 把青蛙救回来
Or twenty years, we should always be trying to put them back.
即使最艰难的情况 也不会影响Marantelli
Argo: even the most dire situation won't deter Marantelli.
这些斑纹树蛙 受水中的壶菌影响很大
These spotted tree frogs have been struck hard by chytrid.
树蛙曾经生活在水中 真菌杀死所有的树蛙
On the stream where they once lived, the fungus wiped out an entire population.
只有一只雄性蛙幸免遇难
Only one male was spared.
这是在雌性蛙的帮助下实现的
With the help of captive females,
Marantelli把灭绝后的树蛙 又救了回来
Marantelli bred them back from extinction --
三年前
And three years ago,
Marantelli就开始放回青蛙 即使河水中有壶菌
They began returning frogs, despite the presence of chytrid.
小组每个春天都回来 寻找生还者
Each spring, the team comes back to look for survivors.
我们没其它办法 只好帮助这些青蛙产生抗菌能力
Marantelli: we have no other choice but to help these frogs develop resistance.
虽然我们要养殖很多青蛙
Even if we have to breed so many frogs
并把它们放回野外 95%的青蛙都死掉了
And put them out there where 95% of them die.
哪些还活着?
Who doesn't die?
产生抵抗能力的青蛙
The resistant ones.
我们要做的是 引导青蛙进化
What we're trying to do is drive evolution,
使青蛙和壶菌一起生活
So these frogs will be able to live with chytrid.
不要动 小蛙蛙!
Don't you move, little froggie!
[ 笑 ]
[ laughs ]
抓到了! 你抓到它了吗？
Got him! Did you catch him?
抓到了 看！
Yeah, look at that.
这是我们养的小蛙
That's one of our babies.
就在这里 壶菌令青蛙灭绝
This is where they were wiped out by the chytrid fungus.
我们挽救了青蛙 使它幸免于灭绝
We've just brought a frog back from extinction.
这样做再好不过了
You can't do much better than that.
青蛙在实验室中长大 我们把它们放回水中
They grew up in our lab, we put them back, and we've been able to find them
放回两三年后 我们依然能够找到它们
Even two and three years after we've let them go.
发现它们在壶菌中生存下来了
To find them surviving with the chytrid fungus
这表明我们可以把青蛙放回野外
Shows us that we can put frogs back,
青蛙能够和壶菌一起生存 这带给我们希望
They can live here with the fungus, and it gives us some real hope.
看上去 青蛙胜了这个回合
Argo: it looks like the frog might be winning this round.
但是面临着各个方面的压力
But with pressures coming from so many directions,
应对危机意味着 在各个前线发动攻击
Stemming the crisis means attacking it on every front --
无论是壶菌 还是栖息地丧失
Whether it's chytrid, or habitat loss.
在乔治亚州的中部
Here in the heart of georgia,
亚特兰大植物公园一直专注于植物
The atlanta botanical gardens used to focus only on plants.
12年前 公园决定为两栖动物 提供一些必需的帮助
Twelve years ago, they decided to give amphibians some much-needed help.
现在 公园养殖了超过30种的青蛙
Today they house over 30 species,
很多都是从壶菌蔓延的巴拿马救回来的
Many of them rescued from panama when chytrid swept through.
但是这些天来 乔治亚州的本地青蛙也有麻烦了
But these days, some of georgia's very own frogs are in trouble.
穴蛙几乎丧失了所有的栖息地
The gopher frog has lost almost all of its habitat.
为了把穴蛙从死亡边沿救回来
To bring it back from the edge,
公园是重生计划中的一员
The gardens is part of a head start program.
公园在养殖小蛙
They're raising froglets.
现在公园度过了青蛙 最艰难、脆弱的阶段
Now that they're past their most vulnerable stage,
这些小家伙快能回到野外野外
These little guys are about to hit the road.
Robert Hill从蛙卵开始养殖
They were raised from eggs by Robert Hill,
现在小蛙快要回到野外了
And now they're going back to the wild.
穴蛙就在我们的后院
Hill: the gopher frog is right here in our own backyard.
挽救穴蛙不需要很多钱
And it doesn't take millions and millions of dollars.
我们只需要出手相助
They just need a helping hand.
John Jensen工作于自然资源部
Argo: John Jensen, with the department of natural resources,
他知道把青蛙放回野外 并不是想象的那么简单
Knows that returning these frogs is not as simple as it might sound.
穴蛙丧失了97%的栖息地
The gopher frog has lost 97% of its habitat.
只剩下3%的栖息地
Jensen: when you have 3% of this habitat remaining,
所有的穴蛙都依靠这些栖息地
And all these animals that depend on it,
穴蛙消失的原因显而易见
It's obvious why they're disappearing.
地鼠龟也在这里生活
Argo: the gopher tortoise also lives here.
值得注意的是 穴蛙与地鼠龟共享洞穴
Remarkably, the frogs share the tortoises' burrows,
洞穴大概有10尺深
Which can reach ten feet deep.
穴蛙不仅依靠湿地
Gopher frogs depend not only on the wetland,
还依靠周围的森林
But the surrounding forest.
在自然保护计划的帮助下
Thanks to the nature conservancy,
现在穴蛙的栖息地大约有2000亩
They now have nearly 2,000 acres of protected habitat.
接下来就看穴蛙的表现了
Now, it's up to the frogs.
当你花了大量的时间 来养大这些小蛙
Hill: when you've spent a lot of time raising these little guys up
它们都是来自果冻状的小黑点
From little tiny black dots in a jelly,
心情就像第一天送孩子去上学
It's kind of like sending your kid off to school for the first day.
这就是保护工作
This is what conservation is all about --
不要把保护动物关在动物园里
It's not just keeping it alive in a zoo,
应该养大它 并把它放回属于它的地方
It's breeding it and being able to put it back where it belongs.
如果我们可以减轻一点 青蛙受到的压力
Argo: if we can ease at least some of the pressures on frogs,
我们就能帮助青蛙 不管狂风暴雨
We might be able to help them weather the storm.
在约塞米蒂国家公园 Knapp博士已经决定
Back in yosemite, Knapp has decided
是给这些黄腿山蛙 一些机会了
It's time to take some chances with the mountain yellow-legged frog.
有些山蛙 看上去能够与壶菌共存
A few populations seem to be holding their ground with the fungus.
它们产生抵抗力了吗?
Could they be resistant?
如果产生了抵抗力 它们会重新占领这些湖吗？
And if so, could they re-colonize some of the ponds
青蛙曾经丧失了这些湖
Where the frogs have been lost?
Knapp博士认为值得尝试
Knapp feels it's worth taking the risk.
小组收集了一些健康的青蛙 重新转移它们
The team is collecting frogs from a healthy population to relocate them.
我们要运送这些青蛙 到五六里外的新地方
Knapp: we're going to be moving these frogs five or six miles to some new sites,
然后把青蛙放回湖中 整个夏天
And then we'll return to those lakes throughout the summer,
重新抓回青蛙 用棉签檫拭青蛙
Recapturing those frogs and then swabbing each frog,
以了解青蛙在新环境中 的生存状况
Trying to get a sense of how well they're surviving in that new environment.
每个青蛙都测试真菌 并做好记号
Argo: each one is swabbed for the fungus and given an id.
我们植入标签
Knapp: we insert this little tag,
就像植入宠物的那些标签
That's the same tag that some people put in their pets.
这给予每个青蛙 一个独特的身份区别
It essentially gives each frog a unique identification number,
使我们区分不同时间的 不同青蛙
And that allows us to identify individuals through time.
转移青蛙有点令人难以忍受
It is a little nerve-racking to move these frogs,
因为青蛙转移到新湖
Because chances are good in the next two or three years
经过了两三年 青蛙可能全部都死掉
Following their move to a new lake, they're all going to disappear.
这是最坏的情况
In the worst-case scenario,
你牺牲了那些青蛙
You're sacrificing those individuals
来了解青蛙死亡的原因 这可能有利于整个物种
To learn something that might benefit the species as a whole,
也有利于全世界的两栖动物
And amphibians around the world as a whole.
但是要牺牲那些青蛙 令人非常难过
But it's pretty hard to sacrifice those individuals.
它们并不只是数字
They're not just a number.
青蛙会被空运到新地点
Argo: the frogs will be airlifted to the relocation site,
这是为了避免五个小时背包搬运 造成的压力
To avoid the stress of a five-hour hike in a backpack.
在澳大利亚 救助在继续
Back in australia, the race continues.
壶菌蔓延到山脉
Chytrid has swept through these mountains.
在澳大利亚的阿尔卑斯山
Here in the australian alps,
Kosciuszko国家公园
Kosciuszko national park
养殖了澳大利亚最后几个澳洲夜宴蛙
Shelters the last of australia's corroboree frogs.
公园和新南威尔士的野生动物部门 正在接受一个任务
Parks and wildlife of new south wales is on a mission.
在Gerry Marantelli的帮助下
With the help of Gerry Marantelli,
他们希望挽救这个引人注目的蛙类
They hope to save this remarkable species.
这些青蛙生存了许多年代
These little guys have survived the eons --
青蛙比恐龙还长命
They outlived the dinosaurs.
但现在青蛙濒临灭绝
But now they're blinking out.
野外的种类少于200种
Fewer than 200 remain in the wild.
紧急措施启动了
As an emergency measure,
去年秋天 1000个澳洲夜宴蛙蝌蚪 被放回无壶菌的水域
Last fall, 1,000 corroboree tadpoles were released into tubs of chytrid-free water.
就在这些受保护的育种区
In these protected nurseries,
大家希望这些小家伙
It's hoped that the youngsters will make it through
能够度过最脆弱的时期
Their most vulnerable stage, and develop
并发展出应对野外壶菌的抗体
A resistance to the fungus in the wild.
公园和野生动物组织的Marantelli和dave hunter
Marantelli and dave hunter from parks and wildlife
回来了解 青蛙能否度过冰冷的冬天
Are back to see if any survived the icy winter.
噢 那里有一只!
Marantelli: oh, there's one!
这里也有蝌蚪
Tadpoles here, too.
如释重负
Hunter: that's a huge relief.
我们的小蝌蚪怎么样了?
Marantelli: how are our little taddies?
噢 那里有两只
Oh, there's two in there.
这儿有一些
There's some in this one.
这里有很多蝌蚪
And lots of taddies in this one.
这里也有蝌蚪 真奇妙
Tadpoles here, too. Fantastic.
这里也有蝌蚪
And taddies in this one.
我们会拯救青蛙
Marantelli: we're going to save
救得越多越好
Some of them, and we're going to save as many as we can.
我希望在这些青蛙灭绝前 做一些恰当的事情
I hope that we get it right before these guys go extinct.
我们必须行动起来 解决这个难题
We have to do something about fixing this problem.
如果我们什么都不做
If we don't do that,
我们就大错特错了
As humans, then there's something wrong with all of us.
人人都应该行动起来 保护当地的青蛙
Everybody has to act locally to do something about it.
如果我们现在还不行动
If we don't act now,
就再也没有时间 来改变青蛙的命运了
There might not be time to turn it around.
走过青蛙的栖息地 我非常难受
It's incredibly sad to wander through a habitat
看到青蛙一度繁荣昌盛的地方
And see where a frog once lived.
我站在溪流旁 却悄然无声
I've stood in streams that were silent,
我听见全球许多地方 青蛙在灭绝
And i've listened all over the world to places where frogs have vanished,
鬼魂在这些地方
And the ghosts are there.
我感觉到 那是灭绝生物的鬼魂
You know, I feel the ghosts of those creatures.
我们再也不能 令同样的事情发生了
We just can't keep letting that happen.
令人惊奇的是
It's amazing -- there used to be
过去这里每平方米都有几百只青蛙
As many as a hundred of these to every square meter.
我希望某一天
I really hope one day
我带着孩子回到这里
I can bring my kids back here
发现这里每平方米 都有几百个青蛙了
And find a hundred to a square meter once again.
但是现在青蛙的情况不太好
But it's not looking too good for this guy at the moment.
祝你好运 小伙计
Good luck, little fellow.
本节目DVD价格19.99美元（不含运费）
For $19.99 plus shipping.m is available on dvd
请拨1-800-336-1917订购
To order, call 1-800-336-1917.
需要更多的相关资讯
To learn more about
了解”自然“节目
What you've seen on this "nature" program,
请登录pbs.org
Visit pbs.org.